dohahamadairport.com 2018-11-04

# Privacy Notice | Hamad International Airport

## 1\. OVERVIEW

Your privacy is very important to Hamad International Airport (“HIA”) and we understand how important it is to you. We want you to feel safe when visiting our websites or using our services and are committed to maintaining your privacy when you do. We require our employees, suppliers and partners to maintain confidentiality in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

This Privacy Notice (“ **Privacy Notice** ”) (together with our [Cookie Policy](https://dohahamadairport.com/cookie-policy) and any other documents referred to herein) sets out the basis on which we collect Personal Data from you, or that you provide to us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your Personal Data and how we will treat it. 

This Privacy Notice can be changed over time to comply with law or to meet our changing business requirement and the latest HIA Privacy Notice can be found on our website at the following link, <https://dohahamadairport.com/privacy-policy>. 

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation, the Controller is Qatar Airways Group, Q.C.S.C. a Qatari Closed Shareholding Company with its registered office at Qatar Airways Tower, PO Box 22550, Doha, State of Qatar (from now on referred to as “ **HIA** ”, " **we** ", or " **us** ").

## 2\. DEFINITIONS

 By " **Personal Data** " we mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.    

## 3\. WHEN DOES THIS PRIVACY NOTICE APPLY?  

This Privacy Notice applies to the processing by HIA of all Personal Data we gather when you use our website, [www.dohahamadairport.com](https://dohahamadairport.com/) (" **Website** "), our mobile application (" **Mobile App** ") services provided by us or others acting on our behalf and when you interact with us. We will only use your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

## 4\. WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR YOUR PERSONAL DATA?   

4.1 HIA is responsible for the collection and use of all Personal Data described in this Privacy Notice. In this Privacy Notice we explain what Personal Data we collect and use and for which purposes, and to which persons or entities the Personal Data will be provided.

4.2 Please be aware however that our Website and Mobile Apps may contain links to enable you to visit third-party websites, mobile sites and mobile applications for your convenience and information. Please note that we do not have any control over these third-party websites, mobile sites or mobile applications and are not responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide whilst visiting such sites. Such sites are governed by their own privacy policies and not this Privacy Notice. Please refer to the privacy and cookie policies of the relevant third party websites/social media for information on the processing of Personal Data by those websites/social media and their use of cookies.

## 5\. HOW WE COLLECT AND RECEIVE PERSONAL DATA

5.1 We may collect and receive Personal Data directly from you or from your authorised representatives (i.e. persons whom you have authorised, persons who have been validly identified as being you or your authorised representative pursuant to our then-current security procedures), including when you:  

(a)     communicate with us such as by email, telephone, in writing or through our customer services pages or social media platforms; or

(b)     use the Airport or any facilities and services (including Wi-Fi, Website, Mobile App) within the Airport.

5.2 Where you may disclose Personal Data on behalf of another person, you undertake and will ensure that the individual whose Personal Data is supplied to HIA has authorized the disclosure, is informed of and consents to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Notice. Where the disclosure if in respect of a child’s Personal Data, you should do as only as the parent or legal guardian of that child. 

## 6\. WHY DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

**6.1 When you interact with Hamad International Airport (online or offline)**  

**(a) For answering your questions or responding to your complaints or requests

What does this mean?

**  

If you get in touch with us in person, via email, website, telephone, in writing or through our customer services agents or social media or by your authorised representative for the purposes of the relevant enquiry, we will use your Personal Data in order to reply to and answer your question or to respond to your complaints or requests (e.g. to assist you in processing a transaction or in providing technical assistance).

**(i) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **

We will process your Personal Data based on our legitimate business interests in providing customer care to you based on your request and depending on the specific case. 

**(ii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**

For this purpose, we may use your name, contact details, email address, date of travel, origin, destination, your correspondence with HIA about your questions and all other Personal Data necessary to answer your questions. We may monitor or record your phone conversations for training, customer services reasons and quality assurance. 

**(b) To allow you to connect with us  via social media **

Hamad International Airport is active on social media platforms like Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, YouTube, and Instagram. When you contact us via social media, we will use your Personal Data in order to answer your questions and to respond to your messages.

In addition, when you click “Follow us” link on our Websites or Mobile Apps, you can contact us through a variety of communication channels. We provide you with our email address, Website, Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, YouTube, and Instagram contact details for you to send us your feedback.

When you click one of the corresponding icons, you will be referred to the website or app of the applicable third party, whether this is your email provider or a social media platform of which you are a member or subscriber and your access and use of any social media platforms is governed by their own terms of use and privacy and cookie policies.

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?**  

We understand that you require a convenient method of communicating with us being a subscriber to those social media platforms and where you have communicated with us or liked our page or posts, it is in our legitimate business interest to understand your preference and interests.

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**

For this, we use the communication channel you have chosen to use to connect with us and any Personal Data you supply to HIA. This may include your name, address, email address, gender and other Personal Data you have included in your message.  In addition, when you click one of the buttons displayed for example “Like” or “Share” on one of our social media pages to indicate your interest and communicate with your network via the third party social media platform of which you are subscriber or have elected to become a subscriber, the relevant social media platform might place cookies on your device.  To read more about cookies, visit <https://dohahamadairport.com/cookie-policy>.

**6.2 For the use of, development and improvement of our facilities and/or services**

It’s important for us to continue to provide you with our award winning Airport facilities, services and uphold the HIA brand. When you use our Airport facilities and services any Personal Data you provide to any service providers or retailers located at the Airport will be processed by such third parties.  Please refer to the privacy policies of the relevant third parties for information on the processing of Personal Data.  

When you access and use HIA Wi-Fi services, we will process your personal data in order to provide such services to you. 

In order to achieve this, we use your Personal Data so that we can assess, analyse and improve our facilities and services to you as an airport, how often you visit our Website or Mobile Apps, and which pages you click on. 

We also use non-personally identifiable data (aggregated data) to analyse our customers’ behaviour, perform research into market trends through statistical analysis to evaluate and adapt our products and marketing to new developments and to make our promotions and offers relevant to you. Our research results are only reported within our organisation on an aggregated basis.

We also regularly use surveys to find out whether you are satisfied with our service. These surveys are conducted through our Website or Mobile Apps. We use your responses to surveys for quality assessments and to improve your customer experience, for instance concerns with facilities available or ambience. 

**6.2.1.1 What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **

We will process your Personal Data in accordance with our Wi-Fi Terms of Use. 

As an airport and based on our business interest, we will process your Personal Data while we continuously improve our service offering to you when you travel and use our facilities.  To ensure the security of your Personal Data, our research and analytics are aggregated and anonymized and we require our employees, suppliers and partners to maintain confidentiality in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

**6.2.1.2 Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**

For the purpose of developing and improving our facilities and services, we use your contact details such as your email address and contact number, personal details such as your name, and correspondence with us.

For the purpose of providing you Wi-Fi access you will be required to provide your mobile number or PNR.

In addition, we use the Personal Data you entered into a website or app or that were generated by the functionalities you used in a website or app and the technical data from your device such as its IP-address, the pages you visited on our websites or apps, your click- and surf behaviour and the length of your session.

## 7\. COOKIES

We also collect information through the use of cookies. Cookies are small files of information which save and retrieve information about your visit to this website – for example, how you entered our site, how you navigated through the site, and what information was of interest to you. Read more about how we use cookies in our Cookie Policy which is available on our Website at <https://dohahamadairport.com/cookie-policy>.

## 8\. WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA

**8.1 Access to your Personal Data within Qatar Airways Group**

We may disclose your Personal Data to any member of our Qatar Airways Group for business purposes and administrative purposes to provide an overview of your contacts and contracts with the Qatar Airways Group. We may send the Personal Data to countries whose data protection laws may not be as extensive as those in the European Economic Area (“EEA”). HIA employees are authorised to access Personal Data only if necessary to serve the applicable purpose and to perform their jobs.

**8.2 Access to your Personal Data by third  parties**  
We may disclose or share your Personal Data with third parties. HIA may disclose Personal Data we collect or receive, including:

(a)    to you or those acting on your behalf. Where local regulations require, we may obtain your consent in writing for the purpose of allowing anyone else to act on your behalf;

(b)    to third parties including airlines, ground handling agent or other companies to provide a service to, or perform a function for us or who are otherwise appointed by us in connection with the services we offer you including those who are acting as our agent or sub-contractor, including, without limitation, data processing service providers and our legal and other professional advisors;

(c)    to third parties, including law enforcement officials, law courts and government and regulatory authorities: (a) if we believe disclosure is required by any applicable law, regulation or legal process (such as to respond to subpoenas or judicial orders); or (b) to protect and defend our rights, or the rights or safety of third parties, including to defend against legal claims;

(d)    to customs and government authorities, which require by law access to Personal Data. 

In other cases, your Personal Data will not be supplied to third parties, except where required by law.

**8.3 The use of your Personal Data by data processors**  
When a third party processes your Personal Data solely following HIA’s instructions, it acts as a data processor.  We enter into an agreement with such a data processor for the processing of Personal Data. In this agreement, we include obligations to ensure that your Personal Data are processed by the data processor solely to provide services to us.  

## 9\. HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR DATA SAFE?

HIA has taken care to implement safeguards to ensure the confidentiality and security of your Personal Data. We are committed to ensuring that your Personal Data is secure. In an effort to prevent unauthorised access to, or disclosure of, your Personal Data, we have put in place physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to protect your personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, damage, alteration, unauthorised disclosure or access, as well as all other forms of unlawful processing (including, but not limited to, unnecessary collection) or further processing. In order to protect the security of your information, we use encryption technology when collecting or transferring sensitive Personal Data.

We do not intentionally gather Personal Data about minors. We are not able to identify the age of persons who access and use our Website or Mobile Apps. If you believe we have inadvertently collected Personal Data about a minor without parental or guardian consent, the parent or guardian should contact us, and we will attempt to remove this information. If a minor (according to applicable laws) has provided us with Personal Data without parental or guardian consent, the parent or guardian should contact us to remove the relevant Personal Data.

**Retention**

We will retain Personal Data for as long as it is necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected, the legal or business purposes of Qatar Airways, or as required by relevant laws.

When destroying Personal Data, we will take commercially reasonable and technically possible measures to make the personal information irrecoverable or irreproducible in accordance with the applicable laws.  

## 10\. CONTACT US

You can request access, correction, restriction, or removal of the data that HIA processes about you at any time by sending a request to Contact page of our Website. You will also, under certain circumstances, have the right to data portability, meaning that you have the right to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format to transmit those data to another controller. We may charge you a small, reasonable administration fee to respond to your request. Any request must include the following information: your name and address and any other information which may identify you. 

If you feel that we do not comply with applicable privacy rules you have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent data protection authority.

Should you have any questions about the processing of your Personal Data or this Privacy Notice, please contact:

Qatar Airways Group

Qatar Airways Tower 1

PO Box 22550

Doha, State of Qatar

Attention: Data Protection Officer

## 11\. PERSONAL DATA QUERY
